A Finding Aid to the Jacques Lipchitz papers and Bruce Bassett papers concerning Jacques Lipchitz, 1910-2001, bulk 1941-2001, in the Archives of American Art AAA.lipcjacq2
Archives of American Art
- Jacques Lipchitz papers, bulk 1941-1999; circa 1910-1999; Series 1; 9.5 Linear feet Boxes 1-10, OV 11-12; Bassett, Bruce W.; Lipchitz, Jacques, 1891-1973
  - Correspondence, 1926-1975; 1.2; 4.2 Linear feet Boxes 1-5, OV 11
    - Plass, Mrs. Webster - Portable Gallery Press, 1945-1970 (Box 3, Folder 46)
      Plass, Mrs. Webster
      Play Schools Association Inc.
      Pleiss, Margo
      Poe, Barbara Reis
      Pollack, Jack Harrison
      Pomerance, Harriet and Leon
      Pomerance and Breines Architects
      Pomfret School
      Portable Gallery Press
    - Portland Art Museum, 1950-1951 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Portland Museum Art School - Ragon, Sara, 1944-1973 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      Portland Museum Art School
      Powers, Judith
      Praeger, B. M.
      Pratt Institute
      Prentice-Hall, Inc.
      Primus Gallery
      Princeton University, Art Museum
      Prisme des Arts
      Prochnik, Wit-Olaf
      Pro Civitate Christiana
      Provincetown Art Association Incorporated
      Public Education Association
      Purris, J. J.
      Quamme, Norman
      Racine Art Foundry
      Racolin, Alexander E.
      Rácz, Andre
      Radcliffe Institute for Independent Study
      Radiodiffusion-Télévision Française
      Radziminski, Wayne Lee
      Raemith, Waldemar
      Rafi, Samir
      Ragon, Sara
    - Rannit, Aleksis - Redstone, Louis G. and Ruth, 1952-1972 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      Oversized material housed in OV 11, F4
      Rannit, Aleksis
      Rapoport, Morris
      Rapoport, Natan
      Rassegna Internazionale di Scultura Contemporanea all'Aperto, 2a
      Ray, Deborah Cohen
      Raynal, Germaine and M.
      Read, Prudence
      Rechter Zary Architects, Peri Engineer
      Reder, Bernard
      Redstone, Louis G. and Ruth
    - Refess-Remisoff, Michel and Hélène - Reform Jewish Appeal, 1954-1969 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      Refess-Remisoff, Michel and Hélène
      Reform Jewish Appeal
    - Reis, Bernard and Becky; Reis, Barbara, 1952-1964 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Rewald, John - Rienckens, Valentin, 1943-1969 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Rewald, John
      Rey, Sydor
      Rhode Island School of Design, The Museum
      Rice, Norman N.
      Richter, Horace
      Rienckens, Valentin
    - Rijksmuseum Kröller Muller Otterlo, 1953-1968 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Rimberg, Herman - Rosch, Mrs. Samuel J., 1943-1970 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      Rimberg, Herman
      Rina Gallery
      Ringelheim, Paul H.
      Ritter, Gladys
      Robbins, Dorothy
      Robinson, George F.
      Rockefeller, Mrs. John D., III
      Rockefeller, Mary C.
      Rockefeller, Nelson A.
      Rodgers, William
      Rodman, Selden
      Romain Rolland Memorial Meeting
      Rome, Harold
      Ronnebeck, Arnold
      Rood, Dorothy B. A.
      Rosch, Mrs. Samuel J.
    - Rose, Billy - Rozran, Bernard W., 1950-1967 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      Rose, Billy
      Rosen, Jack
      Rosen, Samuel
      Rosenbaum, Helen
      Rosenberg, Natalie
      Rosenberg, James N.
      Rosenfeld, Louis
      Rosenthal, Julius
      Rosgate, Theodore
      Ross, Gloria and Arthur
      Roston, Arnold
      Roth, Irene
      Roth, Sanford H.
      Rotsch, Kurt
      Rousset, Robert
      Rowlings, Arnie
      Royal-Athena Galleries
      Rozran, Bernard W.
    - Rubin, Samuel - R.V. Replogle and M. G. Barr, Designers and Directors of Apex, 1955-1964 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      Rubin, Samuel
      Rubinow, Raymond S.
      Rubinson, Nathan
      Rubinstein, Marla
      Rudier, G.
      Rumsey, Claire
      Ruslander, Selwyn D.
      Russell, Dick and Steph
      Russell, George
      R.V. Replogle and M. G. Barr, Designers and Directors of Apex
    - Sadwith, Lucille - Sarah Lawrence College, 1951-1967 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      Sadwith, Lucille
      Sahl, Hans
      Saint Cloud State College
      St. Joseph Museum
      St. Paul Gallery and School of Art
      Sts. John and Paul School (Larchmont, NH)
      Salcius, Mr. A.
      Salmony, Alfred
      Sandberg, Willem
      Sanders, P.
      San Francisco Civic Center Plaza International Competition
      San Francisco Museum of Art
      Sarah Lawrence College
    - Scarsdale Studio Workshop - Schneersohn, I., 1957-1969 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      Scarsdale Studio Workshop (NY)
      Scarsdale Synagogue (NY)
      Scarsdale Woman's Club (NY)
      Schaap, Adolf
      Schack, William
      Schalz, Belle K.
      Schapiro, Meyer and Lillian
      Schendel, Jim
      Scher, Marie
      Schmid, Elsa
      Schneersohn, I.
    - Schneerson, Menachem M., 1959-1967 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Schneid, Otto - Sculptors Guild, Incorporated, 1942-1966 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      Schneid, Otto
      Schneider, Alexander
      Schocken, Gidon
      Schor, Ilya
      Schuling, I. W.
      Schwartz, Alan E.
      Schwarz, Karl
      Schweich, Albert
      Schweicher, Curt
      Schweighofer, F.
      Schweinhage, Karin M. E.
      Sculptors Guild, Incorporated
    - Seattle World's Fair - Sextant, Inc., 1944-1970 (Box 4, Folder 15)
      Seattle World's Fair
      Seckler, Dorothy
      Segel, Yonny
      Segy Gallery
      Seiden, Rudolph
      Setterblad, Oscar
      Sexology
      Sextant, Inc.
    - Shapiro, Jessie - Silvermine Guild of Artists, Inc., 1952-1969 (Box 4, Folder 16)
      Shapiro, Jessie
      Shaw, Frederick W.
      Shaye, Max M.
      Sherer, Morris
      Sherman, Devora
      Sherod
      Shikes, Peter B.
      Shopen, Ken
      Shore, Donald
      Shorewood Publishers Inc.
      Show
      Sichel, Pierre
      Sicilia, Salvatore
      Sikkens Lakfabrieken
      Silber, Zavel
      Silvermine Guild of Artists, Inc.
    - Simms, Carroll H. - Smithsonian Institution, National Collection of Fine Arts, 1953-1970 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      Simms, Carroll H.
      Sinai Temple (Los Angeles)
      Singer, Herbert M.
      Singer, Mimi
      Skidmore, Owings and Merrill, Architects/Engineers
      Sleepy Hollow Restorations
      Sloan, Mrs. N. P.
      Smith College Museum of Art
      Smith, Hinchman and Grylls Associates, Inc.
      Smith, Jean Kennedy
      Smithsonian Institution, National Collection of Fine Arts
    - Smoter, Jerzy - Sonnenfeld, Otto, 1949-1968 (Box 4, Folder 18)
      Smoter, Jerzy
      Soby, James T.
      Sobsy, Cynthia
      Société des Amis d'Yvan Goll
      Société Radio-Canada
      Society of Washington Artists
      Soderberg, Ronald
      Sofianopulo, Cesare
      Solomon, Betty M.
      Solomon, Gerald
      Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum
      Sonnenberg, Benjamin
      Sonnenfeld, Otto
    - Soula, Camille, 1951-1963 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Southworth, June - Soyer, Raphael, 1962-1966 (Box 4, Folder 20)
      Southworth, June
      Soyer, Raphael
    - Spaeth, Eloise, 1962-1964 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Spalek, Paul - Stankiewicz, Richard, 1946-1971 (Box 4, Folder 22)
      Spalek, Paul
      Spampinato, Mario
      Spanish Refugee Aid, Inc.
      Spanish Refugee Appeal
      Spire Production Company
      Spring, Betty
      Spring, John C.
      Springfield Art League (MA)
      Squier, Jack
      Stadt Duisberg Kunstmuseum
      Stadt Köln
      Stadtische Kunstsammlungen, Nuremberg
      Städtisches Museum Wuppertal
      Staempfli, George W.
      Stankiewicz, Richard
    - Starrels, Joel and Celeste, 1958-1967 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Starwood Corporation - Stavisky, Lotte, 1949-1964 (Box 4, Folder 24)
      Starwood Corporation
      State of Israel Bonds
      State of Israel Commemoration Dinner
      State University of Iowa
      Stavisky, Lotte
    - Stedelijk Museum (Amsterdam), 1955-1963 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Stedelijk Museum "Het Prinsehof" (Delft) - Stephens, Jacqueline, 1928-1966 (Box 4, Folder 26)
      Stedelijk Museum "Het Prinsehof" (Delft)
      Stedelijk van Abbe-museum (Eindhoven)
      Steegmuller, Francis
      Steendrukkerij de Jong and Co.
      Stein, Gertrude (photocopies)
      Stein, Jules
      Steinbeck, Dietmar
      Steinman, Mr. and Mrs.
      Stephens College
      Stephens, Jacqueline
    - Sterling, Friede and Bob - Tafel, Edgar, 1944-1966 (Box 4, Folder 27)
      Sterling, Friede and Bob
      Stern, Herbert
      Stern, Louis E.
      Stern, Simone
      Streeter, Tal
      Strutz, Henry
      Stuart Art Gallery
      Sunday Courier and Press (Evansville, IN)
      Sweeney, James Johnson
      Swet, Gershon
      Tacha, Athena C.
      Tafel, Edgar
    - Taft, Robert, Jr., 1957-1960 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Talner, Gabrielov, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Tamarind Lithography Workshops, Inc., 1962-1969 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Tasutzky, Boris - Teochita, Inc., Pre-Columbian Art, 1952-1968 (Box 4, Folder 31)
      Tasutzky, Boris
      Tate Gallery
      Taylor, Larry P.
      Taylor, Sandra
      Tell, Philip
      Teller, Walter Magnes
      Temerman, Nadia
      The Temple (Cleveland)
      Temple Beth El (Flint, MI)
      Temple B'nai Sholom
      Temple Emanu-el of Long Beach (NY)
      Temple Israel (Croton-on-Hudson, NY)
      Temple Israel of Northern Westchester (NY)
      Temple Sinai of Bergen County (NJ)
      Tenenbaum, Sheu
      Teochita, Inc., Pre-Columbian Art
    - Thaler, Pat - Tishman, Ruth W., 1945-1964 (Box 4, Folder 32)
      Thaler, Pat
      Thalheimer, Lilyan J.
      Thannhauser, Justin K.
      Thebault, Janine
      Thebault, P. F.
      Theodor Herzl Institute
      This Week Magazine
      Thomas, Steffen
      Thompson, G. David
      Thompson, Gladys
      Ticho, Anna
      Tillinghast, Caroline and Frank
      Time
      Times Herald Record (Middletown, NY)
      Tishman, Paul
      Tishman, Ruth W.
    - Tobak, David - Tovish, Harold, 1952-1972 (Box 4, Folder 33)
      Tobak, David
      Tobias, Frances
      Toledo Museum of Art
      Tombeau du Martyr Juif Inconnu
      Tommasi, Paolo
      Tompkins, Alfred E.
      Tournai [Belgium], Municipality of
      Tovish, Harold
    - Trepuk, Albert O. - Union of Hebrew American Congregations, Commission on Synagogue Administration, 1947-1973 (Box 4, Folder 34)
      Trepuk, Albert O.
      Trier, Eduard
      Trotsky, Hélène
      Trumbull Jewish Community Group (CT)
      Tuchman, Mr.
      Tucker, Jean S.
      Tung Hsun-Chung
      Turnbull, Grace H.
      Turn Toward Peace, New England Regional Office
      l'Union des Artistes, Centenaire Toulouse-Lautrec
      Union des Sociétés Juives de France
      Union of Hebrew American Congregations, Commission on Synagogue Administration
    - United Church Board for Homeless Ministries - University of California, 1942-1970 (Box 4, Folder 35)
      United Church Board for Homeless Ministries
      United Church of Christ (Philadelphia)
      United Hebrew Congregation (St. Louis)
      United Jewish Appeal of Greater New York
      United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO)
      United Presbyterian Church
      United States Department of State
      United States Information Agency
      United States Treasury Department
      United States War Information Office
      United States War Production Board
      Universal Limited Art Editions
      University of California
    - University of California, Los Angeles, Art Galleries, 1960-1967; 2 Folders (Box 4, Folder 36-37)
    - University of Chicago - University of Kansas, Museum of Art, 1946-1963 (Box 4, Folder 38)
      University of Chicago
      University of Denver
      University of Hartford
      University of Illinois, Krannert Art Museum
      University of Kansas
      University of Kansas, Museum of Art
    - University of Minnesota, Duluth, 1961-1969; 2 Folders (Box 4, Folder 39-40)
      Oversized material housed in OV 11, F5
    - University of Oregon - University of Pennsylvania, 1950-1970 (Box 4, Folder 41)
      University of Oregon
      University of Pennsylvania
    - University of Pennsylvania, University Museum, 1951-1972; 2 Folders (Box 4, Folder 42-43)
    - University of St. Thomas (Houston) - Vacheron, Edilbert Z., 1953-1969 (Box 4, Folder 44)
      University of St. Thomas (Houston)
      University of Southern California
      University of Texas
      University of Toronto
      University of Vermont
      University of Washington
      University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee
      Uris Building Corporation
      Uzielli, Mrs. Giorgio
      Vacheron, Edilbert Z.
    - Valentin, Curt, Estate of, 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Van Bork, Bert, 1960-1966 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Vancouver Art Gallery - Vermont Marble Company, 1951-1969 (Box 4, Folder 47)
      Vancouver Art Gallery
      van der Blij, K. J.
      van der Marck, J.H.M.
      van der Wal, G.
      van Leyden, Karin
      Van Waveren, Godfried
      Varèse, Edgard
      Varkell, Paul
      Vaughn, Rosa E.
      Verdel, A.
      Verhagen, Joep
      Verlag Kurt Desch München
      Vermont Marble Company
    - Victor Kamkin, Inc. Bookstore - Vilven, Marsha L., 1945-1963 (Box 4, Folder 48)
      Victor Kamkin, Inc. Bookstore
      Victoria and Albert Museum
      View
      Villanueva, Carlos Raúl
      Vilven, Marsha L.
    - Vincent G. Kling and Associates, 1966-1972 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts - Waits, Don, 1945-1967 (Box 4, Folder 50)
      Virginia Museum of Fine Arts
      Vizer, Mr.
      Vogel, Virginia Booth
      Vogue
      Vose Galleries of Boston, Inc.
      Waits, Don
    - Walker Art Center, 1954-1964 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Walker Foundation - Weill, Erna, 1948-1969 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      Walker Foundation
      Walker, Maynard
      Wall Street Synagogue
      Walters Art Gallery
      Warren, Katherine
      Warshaw, Howard
      Warszawski, Marie
      Washington Hebrew Congregation
      Washton, Rose-Carol
      Watson, Thomas J., Jr.
      Waxman, Bertha B.
      W. B. Yeats Memorial Committee
      WCAU-TV 10
      W. C. Cox and Company
      Webb, Aline
      Weidenfeld and Nicolson Limited
      Weil, Florence
      Weill, Erna
    - Weiner, Aline - Welton Becket and Associates, Architects, Engineers, 1945-1970 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      Weiner, Aline
      Weiner, Egon
      Weiner, Lillian
      Weiner, Martin
      Weiner, Norman and Eugenia
      Weiner, Ted
      Weintraub Gallery
      Weisman, David
      Weiss, Florence
      Weizmann Institute of Science
      Welton Becket and Associates, Architects, Engineers
    - Weng, Siegfried R. - White, Robert W., 1944-1966 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      Weng, Siegfried R.
      Wenger, J.
      Werner, Alfred
      Westchester Art Society (NY)
      Westchester Arts and Crafts Guild (NY)
      Westchester Co., Commissioner of Jurors (NY)
      Westchester Day School (NY)
      Westchester Reform Temple (Hartsdale, NY)
      Westheim, Raul
      WGBH-FM and WGBH-TV (Cambridge, MA)
      White House
      White, Robert W.
    - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1945-1964 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Wholden, Rosalind G. - William Rockhill Nelson Gallery of Art, Atkins Museum of Fine Arts, 1952-1972 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      Wholden, Rosalind G.
      Who's Who
      Who's Who in America
      Wichita State University
      Wiggins, Jim
      Wilber, Thomas Brown
      Willard, Charlotte
      Willard Gallery
      William Rockhill Nelson Gallery of Art, Atkins Museum of Fine Arts
    - Williams, Jack and Zeta - Wookey, Richard H., 1943-1966 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      Williams, Jack and Zeta
      Willis, Mrs. John T.
      Wills, Frances
      Wilson, Helen
      Wines, James
      Winnepeg Art Gallery Association/Winnepeg Art Gallery
      Wittenborn, George
      Wittlich, Peter
      Women for Peace
      Wookey, Richard H.
    - Worcester Art Museum, 1943-1967 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - World Federation of the Bergen-Belson Associations, Inc. - WUHY-FM (Philadelphia), 1956-1965 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      World Federation of the Bergen-Belson Associations, Inc.
      World House
      WRCV (Philadelphia)
      W. R. Keating and Company
      W. S. Budworth and Son, Inc.
      WUHY-FM (Philadelphia)
    - Wurtzburger, Alan and Janet - Yale Literary Magazine, 1952-1967 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      Wurtzburger, Alan and Janet
      Yale and Towne Manufacturing Company
      Yale Literary Magazine
    - Yale University - Yale University Art Gallery, undated; 1946 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      Yale University
      Yale University Art Gallery
    - Yamasaki, Minoru - Ysla, Pedro and Gloria, 1944-1969 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      Yamasaki, Minoru
      Yamin, Martina
      Yarre, L.
      Yeshiva University, Albert Einstein College of Medicine
      YKUF Art Section
      Yonkers Art Association
      Young Men's and Young Women's Hebrew Association
      Young, Philip A.
      Youth Aliyah and Fellowship in Israel for Arab-Jewish Youth
      Ysla, Pedro and Gloria
    - Zabriskie, Fanny and Vic - Zymet, Carl L., 1952-1972 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      Zabriskie, Fanny and Vic
      Zach, Jan
      Zacks, Samuel J.
      Zajac, A.
      Zborowski-Bonat, Josephine
      Zeisler, Richard S.
      Zuck, Tom
      Zucker, Henry L.
      Zymet, Carl L.
    - Unidentified (Alfredo - Frankie), 1958-1972 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      Alfredo
      Alice K.
      André
      Claire
      Emilia
      Falya
      Falya and Nina
      Frankie
    - Unidentified (Gertrude and Bill - Marc), 1952-1972 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      Gertrude and Bill
      Gigi
      Giorgio
      Gottfried and Tutti
      Jane
      Jane and Tom
      Janine
      Jean
      Jo
      Joe
      Joel
      John
      Johnnie
      Libby and Louis
      Marc
    - Unidentified (Marie-Eve - Natasha), 1954-1964 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      Marie-Eve
      Marjo
      Martin
      Natasha
    - Unidentified (Nina - The Zs), 1959-1969 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      Nina
      Nino and Marilyn
      Oksana
      Pablo
      Paul
      Pierre
      Ray and M.L.S.
      Sarah
      Sidney
      The Zs
    - Unidentified (Ami - To Whom it May Concern), 1942-1969 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      Ami
      Chers
      Cherie
      Directeur et Ami
      Monsieur le Directeur
      Frau
      Friends
      Madame
      Monsieur
      Monsieur et Ami
      Monsieur le President
      Rabbi
      Rebbe
      Sisters and All Our Own
      Sir
      To Whom it May Concern
    - Drafts of Lipchitz's Letters (multiple letters per page), circa 1950s (Box 5, Folder 18)
      Allen, Miss
      Anderson, Mr.
      Aronson, Prof.
      Birchinsky, Mr.
      Byron, Charles A. (Byron Gallery, Inc.)
      Darland, Dr. R. W. (University of Minnesota, Duluth)
      Edelsberg, Mr.
      Fox, Mr.
      Hills, Miss
      Hursh, Mrs.
      [Ingersoll], Sturgis
      Jacobson, Mrs.
      Karsh, Mrs.
      Kling, Vincent
      [Kollek], Teddy
      Mackler, Paul and Hope (Makler Gallery)
      Miró, Joan
      Moore, Henry
      Murphy, Chancellor
      Picasso, Pablo
      Redom, Miss
      Rudeman, Mr.
      Silverman, Rabbi
      Sullivan, Dr.
      Verder, André
      Betty
      David
      Fred
      Leonard
      Lou
      Philip
    - Illegible Signatures or Salutations, 1923-1972 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Unsigned, circa 1940s (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Fragments, 1956-1970 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Brandeis University, 1968 (Box OV 11, Folder 1)
      Oversized material scanned with Box 1, F24
    - Marlborough-Gerson Gallery, Inc./Marlborough Fine Arts, Ltd., 1964 (Box OV 11, Folder 2)
      Oversized material scanned with Box 3, F11
    - Philip Johnson Associates, 1960 (Box OV 11, Folder 3)
      Oversized material scanned with Box 3, F45
    - Rechter Zarhy Architects, Peri Engineer, 1972 (Box OV 11, Folder 4)
      Oversized material scanned with Box 4, F3
    - University of Minnesota, Duluth, 1964 (Box OV 11, Folder 5)
      Oversized material scanned with Box 4, F39
  - Diaries, 1940-1965; 1.3; 0.2 Linear feet Box 5
    Eleven small pocket diaries contain very brief entries noting appointments and events, along with addresses and phone numbers, notes on expenses, and a few quick sketches.
    Loose items found in the diaries are housed with the corresponding volumes in separate envelopes. This series has been scanned in its entirety.
    - Volumes 1-5, 1940-1955 (Box 5, Folder 22)
      Volume 1: 1940
      Volume 2: 1941
      Volume 3: 1952
      Volume 4: 1954
      Volume 5: 1955
    - Volumes 6-8, 1956-1958 (Box 5, Folder 23)
      Volume 6: 1956
      Volume 7: 1957
      Volume 8: 1958
    - Volumes 9-11, 1961-1965 (Box 5, Folder 24)
      Volume 9: 1961
      Volume 10: 1963
      Volume 11: 1965
  - Writings, 1946-1965; 1.4; 0.3 Linear feet Box 5
    Writings by Jacques Lipchitz include a notebook containing random notes on sculpture. The folder titled "Lists of Sculpture" includes a list of items lost in the 1952 fire that destroyed his East 23rd Street studio. Among the miscellaneous writings are short pieces and fragments about Rodin, William Zorach, Mary Frank, and Natan Rapoport; memories of Modigliani; articles and reflections on contemporary art and the church; and a completed questionnaire about The Struggle of Jacob with the Angel. Speeches, with the exception of a transcript of his talk with students at Boston University School of Fine and Applied Arts, March 12, 1965, are unidentified and undated.
    Among the writings by other authors are catalog essays, student papers, and a speech about Lipchitz and his work. This series also includes transcripts and notes of interviews with Jacques Lipchitz.
    A small number of writings, enclosed with letters, are scattered throughout the correspondence (Subseries 1.1). Most notable is "Homage to Jacques Lipchitz," a poem by John Ciardi, sent with his letter of June 18, 1958.
    Lipchitz's own writings are categorized by type. Those by others are arranged alphabetically by author. This series has been scanned in its entirety.
    - By Lipchitz (Box 5)
      - Artist's Statements, circa 1950s (Box 5, Folder 25)
      - List and Notes about Lipchitz Collection, circa 1940-1965 (Box 5, Folder 26)
      - Lists of Sculpture, circa 1950s (Box 5, Folder 27)
      - Miscellaneous Writings, circa 1940-1965; 2 Folders (Box 5, Folder 28-29)
      - Miscellaneous Writings (fragments), circa 1940-1965 (Box 5, Folder 30)
      - Notebook, circa 1940-1965 (Box 5, Folder 31)
      - Notes, circa 1940-1965 (Box 5, Folder 32)
      - Speeches, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - By Other Authors, 1946-1963 (Box 5, Folder 34)
      Arnason, H. H., "Jacques Lipchitz - The Maquettes" (1963)
      Cocteau, Jean, Untitled
      Cohen, Ruth, "Jacques Lipchitz Exhibition"
      Ingersoll, R. Sturgis, Foreword to Fine Arts Associates catalog
      Meeropol, Robert, Untitled Student Paper
      Rewald, John, Untitled
      Shenker, Israel, "Jacques Lipchitz"
      Sweeney, James Johnson, "Jacques Lipchitz"
      Sweeney, James Johnson, Address at Dedication Ceremony of Joie de Vivre, Albert Einstein College of Medicine
      Tucker, Jean S., Student Paper, "An approach to Mother and Child, 1949, by Jacques Lipchitz"
    - Interview Transcripts and Notes, 1957-1961 (Box 5, Folder 35)
      "Notes on 'Conversation with Jack [ sic] Lipchitz [ sic]'"
      Jacques Lipchitz interviewed by Tal Streeter
      "A Visit with Jacques Lipchitz," by Marc Siegel for television show "Directions '61" (broadcast October 29, 1961)
  - Catalogue Raisonné records, 1992-1999; 1.5; 1.7 Linear feet Boxes 5-7, 10
    Sponsored by Marlborough Gallery, Inc., Alan G. Wilkinson's The Sculpture of Jacques Lipchitz: A Catalogue Raisonné was published by Thames and Hudson. Volume One: The Paris Years, 1910-1940 appeared in 1996, and Volume Two: The American Years, 1941-1973 was issued in 2000.
    The series is arranged as 3 subseries. This series has not been scanned.
    1.5.1: Volume One: The Paris Years, 1910-1940, 1992-1996
    1.5.2: Volume Two: The American Years, 1941-1973, circa 1992-1999